ROBERT FOLTZ

0	Toronto, Ontario, Canada
	+ 1 (705) 796-4981
	rfoltz512@gmail.com
in	linkedin.com/in/robert-foltz-593b6163



Summary

I am a Full Stack Software Engineer and over the years have invested in myself by growing both my technical knowledge and skills both in terms of breadth and depth, as well as challenging myself in the large corporate world working for one Canada's leading banks and then switching over to one of Toronto's pioneering technology start-up's serving some of the world's largest retailers.

At the center of my experience I have always been involved in big-data related initiatives whether it be data analytics in banking supporting key regulatory requirements or data processing and analytics in retail to enable e-commerce personalisation. I have further expanded my experience to go beyond analytics and focus in recent years more on data activation and enabling the use of the data through application services building some of the latest retail personalisation's applications for health and wellness.

Experience

Foodmaestro • Engineering Team Lead • Feb 2018 - Present (2 years 7 months +)
As an Engineering Team Lead Robert managed a small team of developers to develop new customer facing applications, lead customer integrations and mentor his team to become better than they were yesterday.

- Designed and built infrastructure to store and server our data (Azure, SQL, VM)
- Determine scope and breaking down complex features and requirements into ticket (JIRA)
- Building new API endpoints to be consumed by Retailer Frontends (JS/Node.js)
- Maintained Existing Infrastructure for Mobile apps
- Collaborating with Retailers in the UK and Canada to integrate our services

Scotiabank • Senior Programmer • Jul 2014 - Feb 2018 (3 years 8 months)

As part of the Business Intelligence Center of Excellence I'm responsible for helping business lines determine the best approach for their business intelligence projects and plans. By giving them the tools and training to better manage their self-service analytics and reporting visions.

Past responsibilities for designing and developing dashboard reports for many different business lines that are typically consumed by executives. My time at Scotiabank with the help of two other co-workers we've created a new reporting portal that is built using HTML5, CSS and Javascript for the front-end and using ASP.Net for the backend. We have also made a hybrid app for iOS that allows the executives to consume this new portal on the go.

- Scotiabank System Programmer Jan 2012 Jul 2014 (2 years 7 months)
- Created websites into mobile apps and distributed in house.
- Worked with Cognos Reporting tools to create ad hoc reports.
- Helped design / prototype na in-house social networking site. (The other half of the mobile app)
- Used the Agile project management style for software development.
- Helped manage MS SQL stored procedures for reporting purposes.
- Arcline (2000) Inc. Junior Programmer May 2011 Aug 2011 (4 months)

Arcline is a Truck and Freight dispatch software company.

- Worked with Visual Fox Pro.
- Helped maintain Version 2 of the software.
- Used Visual Source Safe for a code repository
- Gave some input Version 3 of the software.
- Learned some of technical terms in the trucking industry.
- Barrie City of Barrie Computer Technician Jan 2010 Aug 2010 (8 months)

I was originally a highschool co-op and they hired me for the summer. I was fixing physical hardware as well as software issues with the companies machines.

Jenkins

- Fixed software related issues.
- Also fixed physical related issues for hardware.
- Imaged machines using Norton Ghost.
- Improved my customer service skills by speaking with customers on the phone.

Education

Georgian College • 2010 - 2013

Computer Programmer Analyst, Computer Science

Skills

Python

Node.jsC#Jira

• Microsoft Azure • GIT • Rest API

• Javascript • Tableau • React

• SQL



